《サクラ : 私だっているんだ。
Don't forget about me!
We're both women,
so don't mock me!
同じ女なら バカにしないで！》
《カカシ : ナルト サスケ サクラ…。
Naruto…Sasuke…Sakura!
うん いい画だ。
今のお前らは…。
You guys make
a nice picture right now.
大好きだ》
I really love you guys!
(サスケ)今だ！
しゃ～んなろ～！
Now!
Cha!
(ナルト)よっしゃ～！
All right!
(２人)六道地爆天星。
Six Paths Planetary Devastation!
《カグヤ : またしても→
To think that I,
the originator of chakra…
このチャクラの祖である わらわが→
このような分散したチャクラどもに
敗れるとは…》
would be defeated by pieces of
my own chakra, again…
《カグヤ : なぜだ!?》
Why?!
《ハゴロモ : フッ やりよったか。
Hmm? They've done it!
あとは お前たちを
連れ戻すだけだ》
All that's left is to bring
you all back!
うっ！ ぐぅ～！
グォ～！
うわっ！
Is the ground being
sucked up towards her?
大地が 吸い寄せられているのか!?
(孫)やっと出られた。
We finally made it out!
九喇嘛 やるな お前の人柱力は。
Kurama, your Jinchuriki's pretty good.
(九喇嘛)フン…。
オオ…。
グォ～！
CONGRATULATIONS
こっちだ！
Over here!
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
ん？ ナルトはどうした？
What happened to Naruto?
やり残していることを
片づけてくると 一人離れた。
He went off by himself,
saying there was something
he had to take care of.
それより ここから
もっと遠くへ離れろ！
More importantly, we need to
get farther away from here!
At this point, it can't be helped.
(ゼツ)こうなってはしかたない。
また次の母復活へ向け…。
I'll just start over and work on
Mother's next resurrection!
そういや お前
親離れしたくねえんだったな。
That reminds me,
you don't like being separated
from your mom, right?
き 貴様！
D-Damn you!
今までずっと陰に隠れて
コソコソしてたお前のことだって→
I haven't forgotten about you.
Hiding in the shadows
and creeping around for all this time!
見逃しゃしねえよ。
グッ お前など！
You!
ただ俺の作った
忍の歴史の一部！
You're just a piece of
the shinobi history I created.
お前のようなガキに 俺は…。
A brat like you could never…!
歴史？
History?
忍の歴史っつうのは→
Shinobi history…
いろんな忍者の生きざまと
死にざまだ。
consists of all sorts of ninja's lives,
and deaths!
俺は いろんな忍者から→
Many shinobi taught me
what it means to be a shinobi.
忍ってのが なんなのか
教えてもらった。
人の死の悲しみや
戦争の悲惨さ…。
The pain and sadness of death…
the tragedy of war.
それだけじゃねえ。
And not only that!
認めてもらえる嬉しさに
愛される喜びもだ！
They taught me the joy of
being accepted and being loved!
The way they lived…
and the way they died…
みんなの生きざまが 死にざまが
俺に教えてくれたんだ！
made me who I am!
俺に託していったんだ！
They taught me and trusted me!
親離れもできねえ ガキ１人が
勘違いしてんじゃねえってばよ！
You're a brat who
can't even leave the nest!
Get over yourself!
うわ～っ！
ぐわ～っ！
(カカシ)まだ 大きくなってる…。
It's still growing.
まるで 月のようだな。
It's like a moon.
(サクラ)あっ！
みんな！
終わったな。
Guys!
It's over.
封印 終了！
The seal is complete!
これで めでたし めでたし
だってばよ。
We can finally celebrate!
そうなのね。
You're right.
う～ん… まずは お風呂に入って
汗と汚れを落として→
The first thing I want is a hot bath
to wash away all
this sweat and grime.
さっぱりしたいわね。
って… 私たちは どうすんの!?
Hold on a sec!
What about us?!
この空間から
どうやって戻るのよ!?
How are we supposed to
get out of this Time-Space?!
あぁ～っ！ そうだった!!
Oh no! You're right!
This is bad! This is bad!
やることは やる。
だが 少々 アホだな やはり。
He does whatever
needs to get done.
But he's still pretty dumb, isn't he?
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu!
ん？ ん？
(ミナト)おかえり ナルト。
Welcome home, Naruto.
父ちゃん…。
Dad…
ナルト… この人 誰？
Naruto, who's this?
六道の大じいちゃん。
Six Paths Super Gramps!
これってば…。
Which means…
That's right,
you're back in your world
そうだ 戻ってきたのだ。
かつての五影 皆で
口寄せの術をしてな。
through a Summoning performed
by all prior Five Kage together.
(ハゴロモ)歴代の五影に
協力してもらうよう→
I called all of
the previous Five Kage
from the afterworld to help.
わしが 浄土から呼んだのだ。
ナルト サスケ… そして みんな。
Naruto, Sasuke…
and the rest of you…
よくぞ 世界を救ってくれた。
Excellent work saving the world.
六道の大じいちゃん？
Six Paths Super Gramps?
Are you by any chance
the legendary…?
もしかして あなたが 伝説の…。
I am Hagoromo Otsutsuki.
わしは 大筒木ハゴロモ。
通称 六道仙人と呼ばれておる。
Also known as
the Sage of the Six Paths.
でしょうね… 浮いてるし。
No wonder…you're levitating.
ここまでくると もう
びっくりするのも 疲れちゃった。
At this point,
nothing shocks me anymore.
It seems like everything
went well.
どうやらよ
うまくいったようじゃねえのよ。
The Shinobi World sure went to
hell while we were dead.
死んどる間に 忍の世界も→
大変なことになっとるな
まったく…。
Damn it!
It's the first time I've seen so many
Tailed Beasts together in one place!
尾獣が ここまで揃うのを見るのは
初めてだな。
The Sage of the Six Paths, eh…
六道仙人か…。
It feels like we've wandered
into a fairy tale!
まるで おとぎ話の中に
迷い込んだようよ。
So you are the one, after all.
(カカシ)やはり そうでしたか。
先代の五影様を呼び寄せたり→
Summoning the past
Five Kage here and...
being able to bring the Tailed Beasts
and us back from the other Time-Space…
あの空間から
我々を尾獣ごと呼び戻したり…。
こんな神がかったことが
できるのは→
You're probably the only person
who could perform such godly actions.
あなただけでしょうから。
Are you Kakashi Hatake?
お前が はたけカカシだな？
あ… はい。
Oh…yes.
Good job guiding everyone and
sealing my mother away.
(ハゴロモ)よくぞ 皆を導き
母を封印してくれた。
That truly was the work of gods.
これこそ 神の御業よのう。
Oh, no.
いえ 私はほとんど
何もできませんでした。
I hardly played any part at all.
こいつらと
多くの仲間のおかげです。
It was these three
and many comrades.
それに かつての友が
私に力を貸してくれましたから。
And…a former friend also
lent me strength.
That's why I said you
guided everyone well.
だから 言った
よくぞ 皆を導いたと。
Despite losing your way,
お前は迷いながらも
ナルトたちの師で→
you remained Naruto's teacher
and Obito's friend.
オビトの友であり続けた。
でなければ 恐らく母は
止められなかったであろう。
Or else, you likely wouldn't have
succeeded in stopping my mother.
Hey! Kurama!
お～い 九喇嘛！
Were you lonely being
separated from me?
俺と離れて寂しくなかったか？
I missed you!
会いたかったぜ。
Don't talk so loud!
でけえ声出して呼ぶな
寂しくなんかねえよ。
I wasn't lonely.
You have half of me
inside you…remember?
わしの半分は
そっち入ってんだろうが。
アハハハ。
フフフ。
あの九喇嘛が恥ずかしがって
慌てておるわ。
Just look at Kurama,
all embarrassed and flustered!
だが これこそ
わしが思い描いたもの。
But this is exactly
what I had once envisioned.
尾獣たちすら
自ら 協力したくなる。
That there would one day
be a shinobi,
そういう忍が現れたのだからな。
who could move even
the Tailed Beasts to cooperate.
オビトのことも 本当は ナルトが…。
Even Obito was Naruto's doing…
彼が オビトを戻してくれた。
He restored Obito.
そうか なら その話はあの世で
オビトに詳しく聞くとしよう。
I see…
Then I shall ask Obito to tell me
that tale in the afterworld.
ん？ 彼はまだ…。
Is he still…?
(オビト)そろそろ行く。
I‘m gonna get going soon.
そうか。
Yeah…
俺は忍の世界を
ムチャクチャにしてしまった。
I really made a mess out
of the Shinobi World.
いまさら何を言って→
So much that I don't even know
what to say to you before I go.
去っていったら
いいのかもわからない。
最後は敵でなく
友として別れができる。
We're able to say goodbye
as friends, not enemies.
人助けばかりで遅刻していた
あの頃のお前とな。
To the old you…
the one who was always late
because you were helping others.
俺にとっては それだけでいい。
That's plenty enough for me.
(オビト)ありがとな カカシ。
Thanks, Kakashi.
I'll be going then.
じゃあな もう行くよ。
I've been keeping Rin waiting.
リンを待たせてっから。
(カカシ)
遅刻の言い訳は考えてあるのか？
Do you have an excuse ready?
I told her beforehand
I'd be helping you.
お前を助けてくるって
前もって言っといた。
そうか。
I see…
Same here…
《カカシ : こっちこそ…。
ありがとな オビト》
Thank you, Obito.
カカシ先生！
Kakashi Sensei!
あ… サクラ すまない。
Sakura… Thank you.
はっ カカシ先生
目が…。
Kakashi Sensei, your eyes!
Yeah…
ああ 写輪眼のカカシも
今日で終わりだ。
As of today, Kakashi of
the Sharingan is no more.
Madara was a Jinchuriki.
Even if it was temporary…
マダラは一度 人柱力となった。
尾獣たちが抜けた今
助からん。
emptied of the Tailed Beast,
he won't last long.
It's his fault for trying
to use such things.
そんなものを利用するから
ああなる。
サスケ ナルト。
Sasuke, Naruto…
Behold, the end of
your predecessors.
お前たちの前任者の最後だ。
You should watch this closely.
見ておくといい。
Is that you, Hashirama?
(マダラ)柱間… か？
(柱間)うむ。
I guess neither you,
nor I could achieve what we wanted.
お前も… 俺も…。
望んでも 届かない…
ものだな…。
It's never that easy!
そう簡単にいくか。
Our job is to do all that we can,
while we're alive.
俺たちの生きてる間に
できることはしれてる。
だから託していかねばな。
And then, bequeath the rest for
future generations to accomplish.
先の者がやってくれる。
相変わらず… 甘いな。
So naïve…
as usual.
フフフ。
お前は いつも…
楽観的だった。
You…were always…the optimist.
But perhaps…
だが それが
正しいのかもしれんな…。
that is the correct path.
My dream…
俺の夢は ついえた。
was squashed.
But your dream…
だが… お前の夢は
まだつながって… いる。
still lives on.
We were both too hasty.
急ぎすぎたな。
We didn't need to fulfill
our dreams ourselves.
俺たちは届かなくても
よかったのだ。
It was more important to cultivate
those who would come after us…
後ろを
ついてきてくれるもの→
託せる者を育てておくことが
大切だった。
to whom we could entrust
our dreams.
なら俺は無理だったって…
ことだ。
Which means I would
have failed anyway.
Since I always hated someone…
standing behind me…
後ろに立たれるのが
嫌いだった… からな。
When we were kids…
ガキの頃 お前は
俺たちは忍で→
You once said we're shinobi
and we don't know
when we'll die.
いつ死ぬかも
わからぬと言った。
互いに死なぬ方法が
あるとすれば→
And that for neither side to die,
we'd both have to reveal
what's inside of us
敵同士
腹の中を見せ合って→
and pour each other drinks
to toast like brothers.
兄弟の杯を
酌み交わすしかねえと。
だが もう互いに死ぬ。
But we're both about to die.
今なら ただ戦友として
酒を酌み交わせる。
Right now, we can drink together,
as war buddies.
War buddies…huh?
戦友… か。
まあ… それなら…。
Well…
I guess…that's okay…
俺… たちも…。
by…
This is the perfect moment.
頃合いだな。
I will release the jutsu,
free the Five Kages
五影たちも
穢土転生たちも→
and those under the Reanimation.
わしが解術する。
行ってこい。
Go.
父ちゃん。
Dad…
そうだ… 言っとかなきゃなって
思ってたんだ。
Oh, that's right.
I've been meaning to tell you…
えっ。
誕生日おめでとう。
Happy birthday!
本当に立派になったね ナルト。
You've become
a splendid young man, Naruto
うん サンキュー。
Yeah… Thank you.
俺たちは外法の存在。
We're an existence outside
of the rules.
いつまでも
ここにいるわけにはいかない。
We can't remain
in this world forever.
お別れだ。
It's time to say good-bye.
クシナに いろいろ伝えておくよ。
I promise to tell
Kushina everything.
俺ってば ちゃんと飯食ってっから
大丈夫だって言ってくれ。
Tell her not to worry.
I'm eating properly!
好き嫌いしねえで
いろいろ食べてんだ。
I'm not picky and eat
lots of different stuff!
え～と とんこつに
味噌に しょうゆに…。
Like, tonkotsu ramen,
miso ramen, and shoyu ramen…
Oh but, not just ramen though!
あ！
ラーメンばっかじゃねえよ もちろん。
あ～ 風呂も ほぼ毎日入ってるし。
I try to bathe every day!
たまに 木ノ葉の温泉行くし。
I go to the Leaf Hot Springs
once in a while too!
Although everyone just says
I only take quick dips…
みんなには烏の行水とか何とか
言われてっけど ハハッ。
それから えっと えっと…。
What else, what else…
I've made lots of friends!
友達は いっぱいできたんだ。
みんな いいやつなんだ。
And they're all good guys!
And…
それから 勉強はまったく
うまくいかなかったけど→
I was really awful at school,
but I never got depressed and
まったく落ち込まないっていう
自信っつうのかな。
had more confidence
than anyone else!
それは 誰よりあったんだよね。
もちろん
三代目やカカシ先生の言うことも→
Naturally, I always obeyed
Lord Third and Kakashi Sensei.
ちゃんと聞いてたぞ。
尊敬してるし。
I respect them both!
They're right here,
so you can ask them yourself!
あっ ここにいるから
直接 聞いてもいいってばよ。
Oh! And those
Three Prohibitions of Shinobi?
あぁ それと
忍の三禁ってやつ？
エロ仙人についてたときに
いろいろ勉強になったってばよ。
I learned a lot about that
when I was with Pervy Sage!
三禁についちゃダメダメだったけど→
He was hopeless
when it came to them though…
but he was
an awesome Sannin
エロ仙人は
三忍としちゃ かっけえ忍で→
and I respect him the most!
いちばん尊敬してんだ。
俺ってば
今日17歳になったばっかだから→
I just turned 17 today,
so I don't know much
about alcohol or girls…
酒も まだよくわかんねえ。
ただ 母ちゃんは→
I know Mom said to find
someone like her…
母ちゃんみたいな女を
見つけろって言ってた。
けど… それは えっと…。
But…that's…um…
Anyways!
とにかく 母ちゃんの言ったこと
全部うまくいってねえけど→
Not everything
Mom told me about went well,
そこそこ頑張ってんだ！
but I'm doing the best I can!
I've got dreams too!
夢だって ちゃんとある。
I'm gonna become an even
greater Hokage than you, Dad!
俺ってば
父ちゃんを超す火影になる。
ぜってえなるからな！
あっちで
母ちゃんにも伝えてくれ。
俺のことは
全然 心配なんかすんなって。
しっかり やってんだって！
わかった。
全部しっかり伝えておくよ。
うっ… うぅ…。